<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<collectionReaderDescription xmlns="http://uima.apache.org/resourceSpecifier">
    <frameworkImplementation>org.apache.uima.java</frameworkImplementation>
    <implementationName>org.cleartk.util.XReader</implementationName>
    <processingResourceMetaData>
        <name>XReader</name>
        <description>This descriptor file was generated automatically by org.cleartk.util.GenerateDescriptorFiles. 

Copyright (c) 2009, Regents of the University of Colorado 
All rights reserved.

Redistribution and use in source and binary forms, with or without modification, are permitted provided that the following conditions are met:

 - Redistributions of source code must retain the above copyright notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer. 
 - Redistributions in binary form must reproduce the above copyright notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer in the documentation and/or other materials provided with the distribution. 
 - Neither the name of the University of Colorado at Boulder nor the names of its contributors may be used to endorse or promote products derived from this software without specific prior written permission. 

THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED BY THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS AND CONTRIBUTORS "AS IS" AND ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE ARE DISCLAIMED. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE COPYRIGHT OWNER OR CONTRIBUTORS BE LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES (INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES; LOSS OF USE, DATA, OR PROFITS; OR BUSINESS INTERRUPTION) HOWEVER CAUSED AND ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, WHETHER IN CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY, OR TORT (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE OR OTHERWISE) ARISING IN ANY WAY OUT OF THE USE OF THIS SOFTWARE, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE. 

</description>
        <configurationParameters>
            <configurationParameter>
                <name>org.cleartk.util.XReader.xmlScheme</name>
                <description>specifies the UIMA XML serialization scheme that should be used. Valid values for this parameter are 'XMI' and 'XCAS'</description>
                <type>String</type>
                <multiValued>false</multiValued>
                <mandatory>false</mandatory>
            </configurationParameter>
            <configurationParameter>
                <name>org.cleartk.util.FilesCollectionReader.rootFile</name>
                <description>takes either the name of a single file or the root directory containing all the files to be processed.</description>
                <type>String</type>
                <multiValued>false</multiValued>
                <mandatory>true</mandatory>
            </configurationParameter>
            <configurationParameter>
                <name>org.cleartk.util.FilesCollectionReader.viewName</name>
                <description>takes the the name that should be given to the JCas view that the document texts should be set to.</description>
                <type>String</type>
                <multiValued>false</multiValued>
                <mandatory>false</mandatory>
            </configurationParameter>
            <configurationParameter>
                <name>org.cleartk.util.FilesCollectionReader.language</name>
                <description>takes the language code corresponding to the language of the documents being examined.  The value of this parameter is simply passed on to JCas.setDocumentLanguage(String).</description>
                <type>String</type>
                <multiValued>false</multiValued>
                <mandatory>false</mandatory>
            </configurationParameter>
            <configurationParameter>
                <name>org.cleartk.util.FilesCollectionReader.encoding</name>
                <description>takes the encoding of the text files (e.g. "UTF-8").  See javadoc for java.nio.charset.Charset for a list of encoding names.</description>
                <type>String</type>
                <multiValued>false</multiValued>
                <mandatory>false</mandatory>
            </configurationParameter>
            <configurationParameter>
                <name>org.cleartk.util.FilesCollectionReader.suffixes</name>
                <description>takes suffixes (e.g. .txt) of the files that should be read in.  This parameter can only be set if there is no value for 'nameFilesFileNames', 'fileNames', or 'patterns'.</description>
                <type>String</type>
                <multiValued>true</multiValued>
                <mandatory>false</mandatory>
            </configurationParameter>
            <configurationParameter>
                <name>org.cleartk.util.FilesCollectionReader.patterns</name>
                <description>	takes regular expressions for matching the files that should be read in. Note that these will be searched for using java.util. regex.Matcher.find, so if you want to make sure the entire file name matches a pattern, you should start the string with ^ and end the string with $. This parameter can only be set if there is no value for 'nameFilesFileNames', 'fileNames', or 'suffixes'.</description>
                <type>String</type>
                <multiValued>true</multiValued>
                <mandatory>false</mandatory>
            </configurationParameter>
            <configurationParameter>
                <name>org.cleartk.util.FilesCollectionReader.nameFilesFileNames</name>
                <description>names files which contain lists of file names. For example, if the value 'mydata/mylist.txt' is provided, then the file 'mylist.txt' should contain a line delimited list of file names.  The file names in the list should not have directory information but should just be the names of the files. The directory is determined by 'rootFile' and the files that are processed result from traversing the directory structure provided and looking for files with a name found in the lists of file names. That is, no exception will be thrown if a file name in the list does not actually correspond to a file.  This parameter can only be set if there is no value for 'suffixes', 'patterns', or 'fileNames'.</description>
                <type>String</type>
                <multiValued>true</multiValued>
                <mandatory>false</mandatory>
            </configurationParameter>
            <configurationParameter>
                <name>org.cleartk.util.FilesCollectionReader.fileNames</name>
                <description>provides a list of file names that should be read in. The directory of the file names is determined by 'rootFile' and the files that are processed result from traversing the directory structure provided and looking for files with a name found in the list of file names. That is, no exception will be thrown if a file name in the list does not actually correspond to a file.  This parameter can only be set if there is no value for 'suffixes', 'patterns', or 'nameFilesFileNames'.</description>
                <type>String</type>
                <multiValued>true</multiValued>
                <mandatory>false</mandatory>
            </configurationParameter>
        </configurationParameters>
        <configurationParameterSettings>
            <nameValuePair>
                <name>org.cleartk.util.XReader.xmlScheme</name>
                <value>
                    <string>XMI</string>
                </value>
            </nameValuePair>
        </configurationParameterSettings>
        <typeSystemDescription>
            <imports>
                <import name="org.cleartk.TypeSystem"/>
            </imports>
        </typeSystemDescription>
        <capabilities/>
        <operationalProperties>
            <modifiesCas>true</modifiesCas>
            <multipleDeploymentAllowed>false</multipleDeploymentAllowed>
            <outputsNewCASes>true</outputsNewCASes>
        </operationalProperties>
    </processingResourceMetaData>
</collectionReaderDescription>
