<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<analysisEngineDescription xmlns="http://uima.apache.org/resourceSpecifier">
    <frameworkImplementation>org.apache.uima.java</frameworkImplementation>
    <primitive>true</primitive>
    <annotatorImplementationName>org.cleartk.token.TokenAnnotator</annotatorImplementationName>
    <analysisEngineMetaData>
        <name>TokenAnnotator</name>
        <description>This descriptor file was generated automatically by org.cleartk.util.GenerateDescriptorFiles. 

Copyright (c) 2009, Regents of the University of Colorado 
All rights reserved.

Redistribution and use in source and binary forms, with or without modification, are permitted provided that the following conditions are met:

 - Redistributions of source code must retain the above copyright notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer. 
 - Redistributions in binary form must reproduce the above copyright notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer in the documentation and/or other materials provided with the distribution. 
 - Neither the name of the University of Colorado at Boulder nor the names of its contributors may be used to endorse or promote products derived from this software without specific prior written permission. 

THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED BY THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS AND CONTRIBUTORS "AS IS" AND ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE ARE DISCLAIMED. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE COPYRIGHT OWNER OR CONTRIBUTORS BE LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES (INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES; LOSS OF USE, DATA, OR PROFITS; OR BUSINESS INTERRUPTION) HOWEVER CAUSED AND ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, WHETHER IN CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY, OR TORT (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE OR OTHERWISE) ARISING IN ANY WAY OUT OF THE USE OF THIS SOFTWARE, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE. 

</description>
        <configurationParameters>
            <configurationParameter>
                <name>org.cleartk.token.TokenAnnotator.tokenizerName</name>
                <description>specifies the class type of the tokenizer that will be used by this annotator. If this parameter is not filled, then the default tokenenizer (org.cleartk.token.util.PennTreebankTokenizer) is used. A tokenenizer is defined as any implementation of the interface defined by org.cleartk.token.util.Tokenizer.</description>
                <type>String</type>
                <multiValued>false</multiValued>
                <mandatory>false</mandatory>
            </configurationParameter>
            <configurationParameter>
                <name>org.cleartk.token.TokenAnnotator.tokenTypeName</name>
                <description>class type of the tokens that are created by this annotator. If this parameter is not filled, then tokens of type org.cleartk.type.Token will be created.</description>
                <type>String</type>
                <multiValued>false</multiValued>
                <mandatory>false</mandatory>
            </configurationParameter>
            <configurationParameter>
                <name>org.cleartk.token.TokenAnnotator.windowTypeName</name>
                <description>specifies the class type of annotations that will be tokenized. If no value is given, then the entire document will be tokenized at once. A good value for this parameter would be 'org.cleartk.type.Sentence'  (especially when using the PennTreebankTokenizer).</description>
                <type>String</type>
                <multiValued>false</multiValued>
                <mandatory>false</mandatory>
            </configurationParameter>
        </configurationParameters>
        <configurationParameterSettings>
            <nameValuePair>
                <name>org.cleartk.token.TokenAnnotator.tokenizerName</name>
                <value>
                    <string>org.cleartk.token.util.PennTreebankTokenizer</string>
                </value>
            </nameValuePair>
            <nameValuePair>
                <name>org.cleartk.token.TokenAnnotator.tokenTypeName</name>
                <value>
                    <string>org.cleartk.type.Token</string>
                </value>
            </nameValuePair>
        </configurationParameterSettings>
        <typeSystemDescription>
            <imports>
                <import name="org.cleartk.TypeSystem"/>
            </imports>
        </typeSystemDescription>
        <capabilities/>
        <operationalProperties>
            <modifiesCas>true</modifiesCas>
            <multipleDeploymentAllowed>true</multipleDeploymentAllowed>
            <outputsNewCASes>false</outputsNewCASes>
        </operationalProperties>
    </analysisEngineMetaData>
</analysisEngineDescription>
